In my memory, winters always used to be really unpleasant.
在我的记忆中，冬天总是非常令人不快。
You had to bundle up just to keep warm when you went outside.
你出门的时候不得不裹得严严实实（bundle up）来保暖。
You were often cold, wet and never more than a sodden misstep away from a patch of black ice.
你常常又冷又湿，而且只要一不小心踩在湿漉漉的地方，就可能滑倒在一块黑冰上。
If you didn't have a nasty slide, you'd arrive home to an ice-cold house.
如果你没有重重地滑一跤，回到家也会发现房子冷冰冰的。
And that would mean turning on the heating and waiting.
那就意味着要打开暖气然后等着。
It's a miracle you didn't get chilled to the bone.
你没有被冻透（chilled to the bone）就是个奇迹了。
Fortunately, things don't have to be so challenging any more.
幸运的是，事情不必再如此具有挑战性了。
Technology, engineering and design have advanced giving us new solutions to old problems.
科技、工程和设计都取得了进步，为我们解决老问题提供了新的办法。
It means dealing with winter needn't be like skating on thin ice.
这意味着应对冬天不必再如履薄冰。
With a smart thermostat, our homes can be toasty when we need them to be.
有了智能恒温器（smart thermostat），我们的家可以在我们需要的时候变得温暖舒适（toasty）。
Many models feature smartphone apps that allow you to regulate temperature remotely, so we can warm up the house before we arrive home.
许多型号都有智能手机应用程序，让你可以远程调节（regulate）温度，这样我们就可以在到家之前就把房子预热起来。
According to techradar.com, the largest UK-based consumer technology news and reviews website, Tado's model features voice control, while the Nest 'learns' your habits and automatically heats the home for you.
据英国最大的消费科技新闻和评论网站techradar.com报道，Tado的型号具有语音控制功能，而Nest则能“了解”你的习惯并自动为你家供暖。
Clothes have been given an upgrade, too.
衣服也得到了升级。
Electronic thermal jackets, hoodies and parkas heat up when you turn them on.
电子保暖夹克、连帽衫和派克大衣一打开就会升温。
What better way to keep snug in the dead of winter?
在隆冬时节，还有什么更好的保持温暖舒适（snug）的方法呢？
At the touch of a button, or through an app on our phones, the clothing generates heat from elements placed inside.
只需按下一个按钮，或者通过我们手机上的应用程序，这些衣服内置的元件就会产生热量。
Many models offer three levels of heating which stay warm for over 12 hours.
许多款式都提供三个加热档位，能持续保暖超过12个小时。
Finally, there is the headgear.
最后，还有头部装备（headgear）。
Beanies and earmuffs that feature speakers included in the fabric using Bluetooth technology so we can listen to our favourite music or, in some cases, have a phone call using the in-built microphone.
针织帽和耳罩织物中内置了使用蓝牙技术的扬声器，这样我们就可以听自己喜欢的音乐，在某些情况下，还可以使用内置麦克风打电话。
All while keeping the head warm and avoiding a chill.
所有这些都可以在保持头部温暖避免受寒的同时完成。
For many, the thought of winter used to be enough to make their blood run cold.
对许多人来说，过去一想到冬天就足以让他们不寒而栗。
But using technology, life needn't freeze up.
但借助科技，生活不必停滞不前。
With the right solutions, there's no reason why winter can't be really, really cool.
有了合适的解决办法，冬天完全有理由变得非常美好。